Father
Отец
Your son is putting himself in another's place
сын тоже судит по себе
Your son now lives outside the palace
Сын сейчас живёт вне дворца
Often must go to the provinces to handle affairs
иногда приходится ездить в провинции по делам
Often cannot be at your side
часто не могу быть рядом когда вы нуждаетесь
When you need me
служить вам
But fear disappointing you
но боюсь вас разочаровать
Dare not slacken in duties
не смею ослабевать в служении
Now
Ныне
Yu Gong committed such treasonous acts
Юй Гун совершил такое предательство
If he returns home
если отправить его домой
His father will surely rebuke him for being disloyal and unfilial
его отец непременно упрекнёт его за неверность государю и отцу
Yu Gong, deeply educated in propriety and law
Юй Гун глубоко воспитан ритуалами и моралью
This punishment
в назидание
Is far worse than execution
куда страшнее топора палача
Good
Хорошо
Well said
Хорошо сказал
This Yu Gong is like
Этот Юй Гун можно сказать
Half a teacher to you
наполовину твой учитель
Having been with you long
долго был рядом с тобой
You can't bear to part
трудно расстаться
Is only human
это естественно
Enough
Ладно
I'll give you a chance
Я дам тебе шанс
Play a game of chess with me
Сыграй со мной партию
If you win
Если ты выиграешь
I'll grant your request
я исполню твою просьбу
Thank you, Father
Благодарю отецгосударь